# Victoria C. Ta

101 Laidley Street #2 · San Francisco, CA 94131 Victoria.C.Ta@gmail.com · 704-239-9136

# **Profile**

Highly dedicated and detail-oriented individual with experience in managing work streams and team members in health initiatives and programs; conducting quantitative and qualitative research, data visualization, and monitoring activities pertaining to healthcare services and various communicable and non-communicable diseases. Experience in leading health activities and presenting deliverables to clients and stakeholders in order to influence program policy decisions.

## Education

George Washington University – Masters in Public Health – Epidemiology, May 2013

Thesis Manuscript: "Intimate Partner Violence and STI among a clinic population in the District of Columbia"

University of North Carolina at Charlotte – Bachelors of Science in Public Health, May 2011

Minors: Biology and Studio Art; Study abroad: Western Europe – Comparing US and Western European Health Systems

#### Relevant Assets

- Statistical Software Systems (SAS 9.3, R, Stata Version 13)
- Tableau, QlikView, QlikSense
- MAXQDA for Qualitative Data Analysis
- Electronic Medical Records eClinical Works

- Certified in HIV Prevention Counseling and HIV ClearView Testing
- Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook, Publisher)
- Languages: Vietnamese, French (Limited proficiency)

#### Experience

Acumen, LLC - Data and Policy Analyst IV (March 2018 - Present)

Client: Center for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), Center for Clinical Standards and Quality (CCSQ) – Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015 (MACRA), Quality Payment Program – Merit-based Incentive Payment System (MIPS)

- Coordinating the production of over 700,000 field test reports and supplemental materials for 13 cost measures across a team of 9 programmers, 10 writers, and 1 contractor hosting the platform for the reports; developing and executing plan for inquiry management of the field test reports with stakeholders
- Overseeing the development of two cost measures which involved the following: communicating externally with 50+ clinicians via phone and email, coordinate meetings/webinars to discuss measure specifications, collaborate with programmers and internal clinicians to run various analyses using Medicare claims data
- Leading the submissions of cost measures to an evaluating workgroup committee by building empirical analyses with programmers and preparing documentation summarizing results
- Produce monthly reports on project activities and deliverables, communicate with clients and contractors in weekly
  meetings on task updates, and tracking deliverables needed for clearance before public posting

#### Deloitte LLP – Advisory Analytics, Senior Consultant (September 2015 – February 2018)

Client: Center for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation (CMMI) – Million Hearts (MH) Model

- Leading project implementation work streams in establishing and refining the processes for patient/beneficiary enrollment, participant organization payments, and monitoring the model's performance
- Developing plans and use cases for collecting and transferring data between the MH Model Data Registry and the Chronic Conditions Warehouse (CCW) enclave for analysis in order to conduct model enrollment and payment processes
- Managing subcontractors' work streams scope of project, timeliness of deliverables, and facilitating discussions between client and subcontractors to ensure transparency of project risks and solutions
- Facilitating and driving client meetings to discuss use cases for process improvement in order to influence business and program policy decisions for the MH Model
- Supporting the establishment of a monitoring plan to maintain and improve overall model performance

# Client: National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) - Business Analytics and Quality Assurance Project

- Extracting, Transforming, and Loading of clinical datasets through mapping to standard data models (i.e. CDISC and ODHSI) and developing use cases of the data as they are loaded into data marts for client use
- Researching methods for sharing clinical research data and incorporated concepts in collaboration agreement with NIH/NIAID client
- Lead in developing the backend of R server for analytics capability of a data portal aggregating Tuberculosis data across clinical settings from various international countries

# Henry M. Jackson Foundation – Measures Of effectiveness in Defense Engagement and Learning (MODEL) Study, Data Specialist (June 2015 – September 2015); Program and Policy Analyst (July 2013 – June 2015)

- Leading MODEL's collaboration with the DoD HIV/AIDS Prevention Program (DHAPP) by computing econometric analyses through Stata 13 on the effectiveness of DHAPP activities, retrospectively cleaning and inputting data into information systems on behalf of stakeholders, providing recommendations for data collection methods, and developing and implementing a study design to measure the effectiveness of tactical and local-level DHAPP activities in partner nations
- Lead in data visualization development and production of DoD global health activities through maps, tables, graphs, and charts for a number of MODEL's briefs, papers, and poster presentations using Excel and Tableau
- Clean, transfer, and code data from the Theater Security Cooperation Management Information System (TSCMIS), the
  Overseas Humanitarian Assistance Shared Information System (OHASIS), and other global-level data in order to provide
  open datasets for MODEL analysts and other interested stakeholders/analysts
- Conduct the Information Technology/Information Management (IT/IM) Systems research in order to contribute to standardizing data collection methods, analysis, and reporting functions for US Military Global Health Engagements (GHEs) and support the development of a learning tool based on the assessment of 30+ extant IT/IM systems
- Publication in Joint Force Quarterly: "Healthy End States? A Descriptive Analysis of OHASIS," illustrating unprecedented descriptive data on OHASIS projects to provide a better understanding of GHE distribution

# Whitman Walker Men's Health Clinic, STI Screener - Volunteer (March 2013 - May 2017)

- Conduct confidential screenings for individual patients on sexual behavior, demographics, and medical history
- Assess patient needs and risk, and administer appropriate STI test(s) based on recent sexual behaviors and partners
- Provide HIV risk reduction and counseling for patients receiving HIV tests and fulfill patient inquiries on sexual health
- Co-Author of Manuscript: "Sexually transmitted infection screening among HIV-negative men and women seeking HIV-testing only: Missed opportunity for HIV prevention?" Abstract accepted for July 2013 STI & AIDS World Congress and poster accepted for July 2014 International AIDS Conference

# Whitman-Walker Health Clinic, MPH Practicum with Dr. Michael Plankey (August 2012 - May 2013)

- Collect and clean data by inputting demographics, screening tests and results, and survey results of HIV negative patients
  completing optional self-tests and blood samples in Excel and eClinical Works medical records database as part of a project
  aimed at testing asymptomatic STIs
- Computing descriptive statistics and multivariate regression analyses using SAS 9.3 in order to identify patterns of intimate partner violence among patients with STIs in the District of Columbia stratified by sexual orientation
- Design study and concepts for Master's thesis based on experience and data gathered/available during practicum

# **GW Tutoring Initiative, Graduate Coordinator (August 2011 – May 2013)**

- Recruit and train 30+ tutors to become effective peer mentors in fostering independent learning and study skills
- Track, review, and follow-up with tutors by assessing work hours and needs by collecting quantitative and qualitative data
- Evaluate quality of services through observations and surveys, and maintain tutoring website
- Successfully increased student usage of campus-wide tutoring services by approximately 50% after one semester

# American Heart Association, Summer Science Intern with Dorothea Vafiadis (June - August 2012)

- Conduct literature reviews on nutrition, health behaviors, cardiovascular diseases, and physical activity; created newsfeeds of articles for professional AHA members
- Provide administrative support for writing Scientific Statements of medical professionals

### Carolina HealthCare System, Service Excellence Department, Intern with Bonnie Felts (May – July 2010)

- Generate Excel data for patient, physician, and employee satisfaction records of Carolinas HealthCare System Hospitals from online databases and distributed surveys in order to collect and analyze qualitative and quantitative data
- Analyze data from patients and hospital surveys to develop suggestions for Service Excellence training sessions

# International Service Learning, Volunteer (July-August 2010)

 Build health clinics, conduct primary care screenings, and triage for underprivileged neighborhoods in Costa Rica and Nicaragua; supervised by Costa Rican Physicians while providing preventative health education

# UNC Charlotte Housing and Residence Life, Resident Advisor (August 2009 – May 2011)

• Facilitate staff meetings, enforce University policy with additional on-call night shifts on a weekly basis, promote and conduct educational events to build strong communities with 40+ residents and Resident Advisors